On the basis of the statements of Saraswati Thakur ...
На основе утверждений Сарасвати Тхакура
We're saying that as the physical
Мы говорим, что как физические,
the subtle and gross bodies are the outcome of exploiting tendency,
слабые и грубые тела есть результат тенденции к эксплуатации,
the swarup, or the spiritual body, is comprised of dedicating tendency
сваруп, или духовное тело, составлен из тенденции к посвящению себя,
of devotional tendencies.
из тенденций к преданности.
Srila Guru Maharaj mentions the concept of roochie-puriksha
Шрила Гуру Махардж упоминает концепт ручи-пурикши,
which means where the guru is examining the roochie
это значит, что гуру исследует ручи,
the taste of his disciple as Saraswati Thakur did to him
вкус своего ученика, как Сарасвати Тхакур делал с ним.
when they come to Cadam Cundy
Когда они пришли к Кадам Канди
And Saraswati Thakur says "which place do you like best?"
И Сарасвати Тхакур говорит: "какое место тебе больше нравится?"
he said: "Cadam Cundy"
он сказал: "Кадам Канди"
then, some years later, the party, again, they run tour
Потом, несколько лет спустя, компания, снова, они отправились в тур
and they come to Cadam Cundy and Saraswati Thakur says:
и они подходят к Кадам Канди и Сарасвати Тхакур говорит:
"your place?" And Guru Maharaj realizes: oh, he's examining the taste
"твоё место?" И Гуру Махарадж осознаёт: о, он изучает вкус
and spiritual tendency.
духовной тенденции.
So, when ... says: ...
Так, когда ... говорит: ...
He signs at the sweeper.
Он указывает на дворника.
Srila Saraswati Thakur said:
Шрила Сарасвати Тхакур сказал:
"If ... is the sweeper in that divine domain,
"Если ... — дворник в той божественной сфере,
then I'm one straws in his broom.
то я одна из соломинок в его метле.
And Srila Guru Maharaj made this observation. He said,
И Шрила Гуру Махарадж сделал это наблюдение. Он сказал,
if we take this as a sincere expression, which we do,
если мы считаем это искренним выражением, а мы так считаем,
he said, then you can understand the unit of construction of the swarup,
он сказал, тогда вы можете понять единицу построения сваруп,
of the spiritual body.
духовного тела.
So, what we take away from this, as with dedicating tendencies,
Что мы возьмём из этого, как с тенденциями к преданности,
the exploiting tendencies are minimized and diminishing,
тенденции к эксплуатации минимизированы и исчезают,
and those which are sustaining the mundane form,
и те, кто остаются в мирской форме,
that means that gradually the layers, karma and ..., they're vanishing.
это значит, что постепенно слои, карма и ..., они исчезают.
As in the roochie-puriksha, Guru Maharaj said,
Как с ручи-пурикшей, Гуру Махарадж сказал,
the guru, in this case Saraswati Thakur, he's beginning to see the swarup
гуру, в этом случае Сарасвати Тхакур, он начинает видеть, как сваруп
manifest on account of dedicating tendencies.
проявляется за счёт тенденций к преданности.